Guide to the Harriet Wasserman Literary Agency Records, 1940s-2000 and undated (bulk 1978-1995) RL.00509
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession 2003-0051
  - Works of authors - Authors files (Box 12)
    - Thomas McMahon (Box 12)
    - Carole Glickfeld (Box 12)
    - Michael K. Meyers (Box 12)
    - Mark Milstein (Box 12)
    - William Jay Smith (Box 12)
    - William Alfred (Box 12)
    - Berthe Amoss (Box 12)
  - Author Files: Victoria Anstead - Richard Bausch (Box 13)
  - Author Files: Richard Bausch - Ruthie Bolton (Box 14)
    Also contains the files of Wayne Biddle.
  - Author files: Ruthie Bolton - Oscar Hijuelos (Box 15)
  - Author Files: Oscar Hijuelos (Box 16)
  - Author Files: Josephine Humphreys (Box 17)
    Contains financial papers, reviews of Josephine Humphreys writing from 1987-1993.
  - Author Files: Josephine Humphreys - Ruth P. Jhabvala (Box 18)
  - Author Files: Ruth Jhabvala - Tom Donough (Box 19)
  - Author files: Merchant Ivory - Eileen Micheals (Box 20)
  - Author Files: Eileen Micheals - Helen Witty (Box 21)
  - Miscellaneous Files (Box 22)
    Contains files and information on Bob Balaban, Jane Doggett, Eileen Micheals, Sigrid Nunez, Laura Otis and Laurel Lee.
  - Author Files of George F. Kennan (Box 23)
    Contains files, drafts, reviews and interviews of Kennan from 1992 - 1994.
  - Author Files of George F. Kennan (Box 24)
    Contains files, drafts, reviews and interviews of Kennan from 1986 - 1991.
  - Author files: George F. Kennan - Ken Culver (Box 25)
    Also contains writing and files on Walter Berns and Berthe Amoss.
  - Miscellaneous files of authors (Box 26)
    Contains files on Ken Culver, George Green, Evan Levine, Francis Mason, Malcolm Turnbull, Jackie Onassis, Daniel Voll, and a draft and copy of Icons by Caroline Winthrop.
  - Miscellaneous letters from clients (Box 27)
    Contains also pictures by Wendy Ewald, and pieces of writing by Laurel Lee and Neva Mullins.
  - Drafts of authors (Box 28)
    Contains drafts of Beyond Happiness by Harry Hartwick, Opium by Carol Lansbury, Natural Enemies by Sara Cameron and Him with His Foot in His Mouth and Stories by Saul Bellow.
  - Saul Bellow files (Box 29)
    Contains a draft of Him with His Foot in His Mouth and Stories by Saul Bellow.
  - Saul Bellow Files (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous oversized materials (Box 31)
  - Saul Bellow Files 1996-1998 (Box 32)
  - Saul Bellow Files 1995 (Box 33)
  - Frederick Buechner Files 1984-1996 (Box 34)
    Also contains personal letters and correspondence of Harriet Wasserman.
  - Miscellaneous author files (Box 35)
    Contains the files of Fred Buechner, Laurel Lee and Emily Arnold McCully
- Accession (2008-0004) 1984-2006, 40 boxes
  Addition (08-004) (18,000 items; 24 lin. ft.; dated 1984-2006) consists chiefly of client files (correspondence, contracts, financial records, etc.), manuscripts and proofs of books by clients, published versions clients, and related materials. Includes especially significant material for Saul Bellow and a few other authors, including Oscar Hijuelos and George Frost Kennan.
  - McIntyre - Williams (Box 1)
  - Winegardner, Mark (Box 2)
  - Winegardner - Zuckerman (Box 3)
  - Abrashkin - Bernstein (Box 4)
  - Alfred - Bolton (Box 5)
  - Bolton - Glaubman (Box 6)
  - Glaubman - Perel (Box 7)
  - Glaubman - Peterson (Box 8)
  - Glaubman - Glickfeld (Box 9)
  - Goldstein - McPhee (Box 10)
  - Grillo - Hijuelos (Box 11)
  - Hijuelos - Humphreys (Box 12)
  - Hijuelos, Oscar (Box 13)
  - Hijuelos - Humphreys (Box 14)
  - Jhabvala, Ruth (Box 15)
  - Jhabvala - Kennan (Box 16)
  - Kennedy - McDermott (Box 17)
  - McDermott, Alice (Box 18)
  - McDermott - Greenwald (Box 19)
  - Anderson - Mitchell (Box 20)
  - Kother - Stonehill (Box 21)
  - Buechner - Williams (Box 22)
  - Myers - Greenwald (Box 23)
  - Price, Reynolds (Box 24)
  - Harrison - Kennan (Box 25)
  - Kennan - Moody (Box 26)
  - Buechner - Markus (Box 27)
  - Markus - Winegardner (Box 28)
  - Saul Bellow Files (Box 29)
  - Saul Bellow Files (Box 30)
  - Saul Bellow Files (Box 31)
  - Saul Bellow Files (Box 32)
  - Saul Bellow and Oscar Hijuelos Files (Box 33)
  - Oscar Hijuelos Files (Box 34)
  - Oscar Hijuelos Files (Box 35)
  - Contracts and Old Tax Papers (Box 36)
  - Contracts and Old Tax Papers (Box 37)
  - Miscellaneous G-N (Box 38)
  - Miscellaneous A-H (Box 39)
  - Miscellaneous - Rejections (Box 40)
- Accession (2008-0078), 1984-2000, 1 box
  Addition (08-078) (8 items; .2 lin. ft.; dated 1984-2000) includes writing samples for agency authors, as well as literary award kits and publications.
  - Writing samples, etc. (Box 1 (Acc. 08/078))
- Accession (2012-0008), 1972-2003, 6 boxes
  Agency files relating to author Reynolds Price, including correspondence, contracts, reviews, and other materials related to his writing career.
  - Price, Reynolds (Box 1 (Acc. 12/008))
    - 1972-1973 (Box 1 (Acc. 12/008))
    - 1989-August 1991, 5 folders (Box 1 (Acc. 12/008))
    - September 1991-1996, 5 folders (Box 2 (Acc. 12/008))
    - 1997-1998, 6 folders (Box 3 (Acc. 12/008))
    - 1999-2001, 4 folders (Box 4 (Acc. 12/008))
    - 2003 (Box 4 (Acc. 12/008))
    - Contracts, 1980-1999 and undated (Box 5 (Acc. 12/008))
    - Royalties, 3 folders (Box 5 (Acc. 12/008))
    - Book designs (Box 5 (Acc. 12/008))
    - Minor contracts, articles, interviews, 1975-2003 and undated (Box 5 (Acc. 12/008))
    - Dinners (Box 5 (Acc. 12/008))
    - Biographies, interviews, good press (Box 6 (Acc. 12/008))
    - Reviews
      - A Palpable God, 1986 (Box 6 (Acc. 12/008))
      - Good Hearts, 1988 (Box 6 (Acc. 12/008))
      - Clear Pictures, 1989 (Box 6 (Acc. 12/008))
      - The Foreseeable Future, 1991-1995, 2 folders (Box 6 (Acc. 12/008))
      - Blue Calhoun, 1992 (Box 6 (Acc. 12/008))
      - The Collected Stories, 1993 (Box 6 (Acc. 12/008))
      - A Whole New Life, 1994 (Box 6 (Acc. 12/008))
      - The Promise of Rest, 1995 (Box 6 (Acc. 12/008))
      - Three Gospels, 1996 (Box 6 (Acc. 12/008))
      - The Tongues of Angels, 1996-1997 (Box 6 (Acc. 12/008))
      - The Collected Poems, 1997 (Box 6 (Acc. 12/008))
      - Learning a Trade, 1998 (Box 6 (Acc. 12/008))
      - Letter to a Man in the Fire, 1999 (Box 6 (Acc. 12/008))